https://www.linkedin.com/in/yoly-pham-1439237a https://yolypham.github.io/portfoliobootstrap

SUMMARY

4.5 years of full cycle development using Java and JavaScript libraries. An Agile enthusiast and self-motivated to leverage technical skills with own time learning and career opportunities. Currently, looking for Full Stack Developer positions using Java, Node, Express, JavaScript, and React.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, JavaScript, ES6, HTML, CSS

Libraries: React/Redux, Express, NPM, Node, JasperReports, Dojo Toolkit, D3, Highcharts,

Bootstrap, Material UI

Frameworks: Jersey 2.x, MyBatis

Database: MSSQL, Oracle, MongoDB

Server: Tomcat

Source/Deployment: Bamboo, Git, SVN, BitBucket, Webpack

EDI: Eclipse, IntelliJ, VS Code

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Densify

Jun 2017-Aug 2018

- · Performed full cycle of web product development with back-end in Java and front-end with Dojo Toolkit, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and JasperReports.
- · Added features of cost/billing analysis, resource balancing, recommendations, and optimization strategies info to the SaaS application used by clients on IBM Cloud, AWS, Azure and GCP Cloud platforms.
- · Maintained and fixed issues in the application for On-Prem VM and Hyper-V clients.
- · Implemented Single Sign-On step from SaaS application to the separate online help web app.
- · Updated the entire web application, reports, packages, and installation program to reflect the new Densify rebranding logo and theme.
- · Utilized Bitbucket, and Git for source and versioning control, and created builds using Bamboo.
- · Collaborated with scrum master, product owners, and business analysts to ensure features are accurately delivered on-time.
- · Worked in Agile environment with 2-weeks spring cycle, performing tasks such as: spring story planning, subtasking, stand-up meeting, spikes, demo presentations, testing, retro-perspective and scrum meetings
- · Performed functional testing and collaborated with QA in the writing and running test cases to ensure features are fully tested before passing to user acceptance test.

Software Engineer | Cirba

Jan 2014-May 2017

- · Maintained and added features to the application related to package upgrade, data audit process, workload analysis, environment refresh, reservation control and data templates for VMware and Hyper-V data.
- Designed and implemented various Java back-end solutions including DAO with MyBatis (MSSQL and Oracle), services layer, and RESP API with Jersey framework.
- · Created front end UI pages using Dojo toolkit, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, JasperReport Studio, and Highcharts and D3 for data visualization graphs.
- · Upgraded old Jasper reports with JasperSoft Studio and published to JasperReport Server.
- · Archived history data via views and script changes for use in reporting database.
- · Worked closely with QA team members to ensure highest quality of code is delivered.
- · Assisted with bug fixes and regression testing.

Production Support Programmer Analyst | Toronto Community Housing Corp Oct 2012-Jul 2013

- · Provided application and database support to the Housing Connections division, a subsidiary of TCHC.
- Worked all aspects of MSSQL database maintenance, plans, job scheduling, db restore and backups, and schema updates.
- · Used Visual Basic to maintain Waiting List client application used by account reps and call center users.
- · Fixed issues in the ASP.NET online application app and maintained website content.
- · Worked with MSSQL, MS Access, VB, ASP, ASP.NET, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and Crystal Reports

Production Support Programmer Analyst (Consultant) | Housing Connections Feb 2005-Oct 2012

- · Provided DB and application support to their Waiting List Management application and the Web application used by providers and online housing applicants.
- · Ran scripts and wrote ad-hocs for management reports and inquiries.
- · Worked with MSSQL, MS Access, ASP, ASP.NET, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and Crystal Reports.

Web Developer | Starlink Systems

Jan 2004-Jan 2005

· Maintained e-commerce web application using JavaScript, ASP, HTML, CSS.

Assistant Vice President | Wachovia Securities | New York

Aug 2002 to Aug 2003

- · Worked supporting and developing mainframe applications for the institutional capital market business.
- · Leaded project of Thomson Financial OASYS institutional order execution.
- · Implemented use of IBM MQ Series interfacing with other apps written in Java.
- · Utilized technologies: COBOL2, VSAM, JCL, DB2 CICS, BMS and IBM MQ Series.

Project Leader, Senior Programmer Analyst | Prudential Securities | New York Feb 1997- Jul 2002

- · Leaded and developed mainframe applications for several business department such as Block Trading, Electronic Execution, Capital Market and Account Information.
- · Coded modules related to calculation of commissions, fees breakdowns, settlement instruction, account information management, FIX and Bloomberg protocol message parsing.
- · Created batch and online applications using COBOL2, VSAM, ICL, DB2 CICS and BMS.

EDUCATION

HackerYou College of Technology

2018 - Full Stack Masterclass: React, Node, Express, ES6, MongoDB, Mongoose, Webpack, Bootstrap

Ryerson University - G. Raymond Chang School of Continuing Education Information Technology

2013 - HTML, CSS3

2009 - ASP.NET

2008 - Visual Basic.NET 3.5

Humber College

2005 - Visual Basic .NET 1.1

New York University - New York

2003 – Enterprise Java Beans

2002 - Advance Java

2001 – Java I, Java II

New York Institute of Finance | New York

1999 – Fundamentals of Security Industry

Bachelor of Business Administration in Information Technology | Baruch College | New York

1997

Associate's Degree in Business Administration | LaGuardia Community College | New York

1994